<healthcare>
  <overview>
    Modern healthcare systems integrate advanced digital infrastructure, clinical workflows,
    and data-driven technologies to improve patient outcomes and operational efficiency.
    These systems are built upon a foundation of interoperability, allowing hospitals, clinics,
    laboratories, pharmacies, and insurance providers to exchange information seamlessly.
    As global health challenges increase, modern healthcare platforms focus on precision,
    personalization, and preventive care enabled by technology.
  </overview>
  <components>
    <component>
      <name>Electronic Health Records (EHR)</name>
      <details>
        EHRs provide structured patient information, including demographics, allergies,
        medical histories, diagnostic imaging, prescriptions, and care plans. They ensure
        continuity of care across departments and healthcare institutions. Modern EHRs
        also incorporate decision-support alerts, lab integration, and electronic prescribing.
      </details>
    </component>
    <component>
      <name>Telemedicine</name>
      <details>
        Telemedicine platforms enable remote consultations, digital follow-ups, and
        chronic disease management. These systems support underserved populations, reduce
        hospital congestion, and allow clinicians to monitor patients from any location.
        Modern telemedicine includes AI symptom analyzers and remote diagnostic devices.
      </details>
    </component>
    <component>
      <name>AI Diagnostics</name>
      <details>
        Artificial Intelligence enhances the accuracy and speed of clinical decision-making.
        Machine learning algorithms analyze radiology scans, pathology slides, genomics,
        and patient vitals to detect early patterns and predict disease risk. AI-powered
        triage systems help prioritize emergency patients and reduce diagnostic delays.
      </details>
    </component>
    <component>
      <name>Wearables &amp; Remote Monitoring</name>
      <details>
        Wearable devices capture real-time biometric data, including heart rate, oxygen
        saturation, ECG, glucose levels, sleep cycles, and activity metrics. Remote Patient
        Monitoring (RPM) platforms notify clinicians of anomalies and reduce preventable
        hospitalizations. These tools support elderly and chronic disease populations.
      </details>
    </component>
  </components>
  <challenges>
    <challenge>Cybersecurity threats and increasing ransomware attacks</challenge>
    <challenge>Data interoperability limitations between incompatible systems</challenge>
    <challenge>High cost of digital transformation and training</challenge>
    <challenge>Regulatory compliance pressures</challenge>
  </challenges>
  <future>
    <trend>Precision medicine based on genomic sequencing</trend>
    <trend>Robotics-assisted surgeries with enhanced accuracy</trend>
    <trend>AI-driven hospital automation and smart ICUs</trend>
    <trend>Digital twins for personalized treatment simulation</trend>
  </future>
</healthcare>